Lowell Thomas Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 2. Phonograph records, 1930 - 1955; 2; Boxes: 1819 - 1839
  - Subseries 2.5: 16 inch phonograph records, 1937 - 1954; 2.5; Boxes: 1826 - 1834
    - “Lowell Thomas, Jr.” Newscast, 1953 (Folder 69.09, Box 1833)
      WCBS-Line; 6:45 - 7:00 pm 2/23/53
    - “Fantasy”, undated (Folder 69.10, Box 1833)
      Produced by Frank Ferrin Parts 1 and 2
    - Lowell Thomas from Ankara, 1947 (Folder 69.11, Box 1833)
      “Feature Story” CBS; 7:00 pm, 11:15 pm 8/2/47 Part 1 of 1
    - Proctor and Gamble Commercial, undated (Folder 69.12, Box 1833)
      for Lowell Thomas Program CBS Show February 23rd
    - Lowell Thomas Program, undated (Folder 69.13, Box 1833)
      Recorded 3/10/53 Band 1-Open.Format & Open.IVORY SOAP Commercial-PSI #18 Band 2-Open.Format & Open.IVORY SOAP Commercial-Bath #2 Band 3-Open.Format & Open.IVORY SOAP Commercial-Bath#3 (for broadcast 3/24-25-26-27/53)
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1953 (Folder 69.14, Box 1833)
      Band 1 - Clos. IVORY SOAP Commercial #17C Band 2 - Clos. IVORY SOAP Commercial #13D Band 3 - Clos. IVORY SOAP Commercial #17C & :15 Blood Donor Annct. (For broadcast week of April 13th, 1953)
    - Gerry O’Brien, undated (Folder 69.15, Box 1833)
      Interviews Lowell Thomas
    - Navy Day, undated (Folder 69.16, Box 1833)
      presented by The Advertising Club of New York WMCA; May 4th, 1939 S1: (1) Introduction by Lowell Thomas (2) Lyn Sumner Takes Over and Introduces Guests S2: (5) Read Admiral Alfred W. Johnson continued (6) Rear Admiral Clark Howell Woodward (of (3) Naval Districts) (7) Closing
    - Navy Day, undated (Folder 69.17, Box 1833)
      presented by The Advertising Club of New York WMCA; May 4th, 1939 (3) Lyn Sumner and Guests (4) Commander Atlantic Squadron Rear Admiral Alfred W. Johnson
    - The New York Advertising Club, 1939 (Folder 69.18, Box 1833)
      Lowell Thomas President March 9th, 1939; WMCA S1:(1) Opening Announcement (2) Mr. Thomas introduces Guests (3) George P. Simon Advertising Director of the “London Daily Telegraph” S2: (6) Mr. Thomas Introduces: (7) Henry Murphy - Architect (8) Closing Parts 1 and 3
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1950 (Folder 69.19, Box 1833)
      Interviewed by Matt McEniry 3/9/50
    - Lowell Thomas, 1946 (Folder 69.20, Box 1833)
      With Lowell Thomas, Jr. and Stuart Syminton at Loulon August 1st, 1946
    - Lowell Thomas Jr., 1952 (Folder 69.21, Box 1833)
      WJAR; 11/4/52
    - “Your Voice Personality”, 1948 (Folder 69.22, Box 1833)
      Elaine Osborn Program WJLK; 7:45 pm 9/15/48
    - Lowell Thomas, 1950 (Folder 69.23, Box 1833)
      With comment from Newark, New Jersey At the Newark Museum 2/28/50; 6:45 - 7:00
    - Lowell Thomas, 1950 (Folder 69.24, Box 1833)
      From Tape May 26th, 1950 - Regular Show CBS; Recorded 5/29/50
    - Feature Story, 1947 (Folder 69.25, Box 1833)
      CBS; 11:15 - 11:30 pm 8/6/47 Part 1 of 1 Turkey, Lowell Thomas, Jr. from Ankara
    - “Lowell Thomas” Newscast, 1953 (Folder 69.26, Box 1833)
      WCBS; 6:45 -7:00 pm 7/27/53 [case says Lowell Thomas, Jr. from France]
    - “Fred Allen Program”, 1946 (Folder 69.27, Box 1833)
      William Morris Agency [sponsor?] WEAF; 8:30 pm 10/ 6/46 Parts 1 and 2
    - Lowell Thomas, 1940 (Folder 69.28, Box 1833)
      Sun Oil News WJZ; 6/24/40
    - Unlabeled, undated (Folder 70.01, Box 1834)
      [Lima, Peru]
    - Lowell Thomas from London, England, 1937 (Folder 70.02, Box 1834)
      Presented by Sunoco May 12th, 1937 (1) Opening Signature & Announcements (2) Lowell Thomas Speaking from London, England; News about the Coronation (3) Closing
    - Lowell Thomas Talk, 1948 (Folder 70.03, Box 1834)
      CBS; 6:45 - 7:00 pm 12/7/48 Part 1 of 1
    - Lowell Thomas - Talk, 1948 (Folder 70.04, Box 1834)
      CBS; 6:45 - 7:00 pm 11/19/48
    - Lowell Thomas (Folder 70.05, Box 1834)
    - Lowell Thomas, 1945 (Folder 70.06, Box 1834)
      Cairo (live) May 21st, 1945
    - Lowell Thomas, 1950 (Folder 70.07, Box 1834)
      (repeat) Lowell Thomas, Jr. from Honolulu 6/7/50; 11:00 - 11: 15 pm
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1952 (Folder 70.08, Box 1834)
      CBS; 6:45 - 7:00 pm 4/22/52
    - “Sunoco Program”, 1937 (Folder 70.09, Box 1834)
      Lowell Thomas June 2nd, 1937; 6:45 - 7:00
    - “Lowell Thomas Broadcast”, 1952 (Folder 70.10, Box 1834)
      Death of King George VI CBS; 6:45 - 7:00 2/6/52
    - Lowell Thomas Broadcast, 1951 (Folder 70.11, Box 1834)
      CBS; 6:45 - 7:00 pm 11/14/51
    - Lowell Thomas, 1950 (Folder 70.12, Box 1834)
      (repeat) Father C[…] Partion [?] CBS; 11:00 - 11:15 pm 4/25/50
    - Dale Carnegie [Carnagey], 1944 (Folder 70.13, Box 1834)
      4/6/44
    - Lowell Thomas, 1945 (Folder 70.14, Box 1834)
      Guam (live) June, 20th 1945
    - Lowell Thomas, 1949 (Folder 70.15, Box 1834)
      Lowell Thomas from Hawaii Charles Collingwood from Washington WCBS; 6:45 - 7:00 pm 7/29/49
    - Lowell Thomas Speaking from the “Queen Mary” in the Mid-Atlantic, 1937 (Folder 70.16, Box 1834)
      Presented by Sunoco May 21st, 1937 (1) Opening Signature & Announcements (2) Lowell Thomas speaking from the “Queen Mary” in the Mid-Atlantic (3) George Sokolsky speaking from New York (4) Closing
    - Lowell Thomas from the Mid-Atlantic, 1937 (Folder 70.17, Box 1834)
      Presented by Blue Sunoco April 30th, 1937 (1) Opening Announcements (2) Commercial Announcement (3) Captain Valentine Williams - Today’s News (4) Mr. Lowell Thomas speaking from the “S.S. Europa” in the Mid-Atlantic (5) Captain Valentine Williams concludes Today’s News (6) Closing Announcements
    - Lowell Thomas from Southampton, England, 1937 (Folder 70.18, Box 1834)
      Presented by Sunoco May 8th, 1937 (1) Opening Signature & Announcements (2) Mr. Lowell Thomas speaking from Southampton, England - “Today’s News” (3) Closing Announcements
    - Lowell Thomas, 1939 (Folder 70.19, Box 1834)
      Presented by Blue Sunoco Sir Hubert Wilkins Substituting WJZ; 6:45 - 7:00 pm July 28th, 1939
    - Lowell Thomas, 1939 (Folder 70.20, Box 1834)
      Presented by Blue Sunoco Colonel Theodor[sic] Roosevelt, Jr.
    - “Kate Smith Speaks Program”, 1939 (Folder 70.21, Box 1834)
      Lowell Thomas Substituting November 9th, 1939 Copy from the original off-the-air recording
    - Lowell Thomas, 1939 (Folder 70.22, Box 1834)
      Presented by Blue Sunoco Dr. Roy Chapman substituting WJZ; 6:45 - 7:00 pm July 26th, 1939
    - Lowell Thomas, 1939 (Folder 70.23, Box 1834)
      Presented by Blue Sunoco Colonel Theodore Roosevelt substituting WJZ 6:45 - 7:00 pm July 24th, 1939
    - “Lowell Thomas Newscast”, 1954 (Folder 70.24, Box 1834)
      With Lowell Thomas, Jr. WCBS LINE; 6:45 - 7:00 pm S1: 2/4/54 S2: 2/5/54
    - Lowell Thomas, 1949 (Folder 70.25, Box 1834)
      Lowell Thomas from a plane over the Pacific Charles Collingwood from Washington WCBS; 6:45 - 7:00 pm 7/25/49
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1951 (Folder 70.26, Box 1834)
      CBS; 11:00 - 11:15 pm 5/25/51
    - Lowell Thomas and the News, 1954 (Folder 70.27, Box 1834)
      With Lowell Thomas, Jr. CBS-Line; 6:45 - 7:00 pm 2/3/54
    - Lowell Thomas, speaking from Paris, France, 1937 (Folder 70.28, Box 1834)
      Presented by Sunoco May 14th, 1937 (1) Opening Signatures & Announcements (2) Mr. Lowell Thomas speaking from Paris, Introduces Premier Blum (3) Premier Blum speaks in French (4) Mr. Thomas translates Premier Blum’s Address & Continues with Today’s News (5) Closing
    - Lowell Thomas Broadcast, 1952 (Folder 70.29, Box 1834)
      CBS; 6:30 - 7:45 pm 1/17/52
    - Lowell Thomas, 1950 (Folder 70.30, Box 1834)
      Korea Invasion Monday, June 26th, 1950
    - “Lowell Thomas” Newscast, 1953 (Folder 70.31, Box 1834)
      WCBS; 6:45 - 7:00 pm 6/26/53
    - “Lowell Thomas Broadcast”, 1953 (Folder 70.32, Box 1834)
      With John Wayne CBS; 6:45 - 7:00 pm 3/31/53
    - Lowell Thomas, 1948 (Folder 70.33, Box 1834)
      June 25th, 1948
    - Lowell Thomas, 1945 (Folder 70.34, Box 1834)
      4/18/45
    - Lowell Thomas, 1945 (Folder 70.35, Box 1834)
      Hugh Gibbons[?] substituting 4/9/45
    - Lowell Thomas from Paris, France, 1937 (Folder 70.36, Box 1834)
      Presented by Sunoco May 4th, 1937 (1) Opening Signature & Announcements (2) Commercial Announcements (3) Today’s News (4) Closing
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1948 (Folder 70.37, Box 1834)
      WCBS; 6:45 - 7:00 pm March 29th, 1948
  - Subseries 2.6: 12 inch phonograph records, 1930 - 1955; 2.6; Boxes: 1835 - 1837
    - Novelty Baseball Game, 1937 (Folder 77.01, Box 1835)
      August 15th, 1937 5:00 - 5:30 pm NBC Blue Part 1 and 3 of 8
    - Novelty Baseball Game, 1937 (Folder 77.02, Box 1835)
      Nine Old Men - Pound Ridge, New York playing George Bye’s Prehistoric Sluggers Gene Tunney Haywood Tisdale and others Dale Carnegie [Carnagey], Lowell Thomas and George Bye speak August 15th, 1937 5:00 - 5:30 pm NBC Blue Part 1 and 3 of 8
    - Novelty Baseball Game, 1937 (Folder 77.03, Box 1835)
      Nine Old Men and Prehistoric Sluggers Play by play August 15th, 1937 5:00 - 5:30 pm NBC Blue Part 2 and 4 of 8
    - Novelty Baseball Game, 1937 (Folder 77.04, Box 1835)
      Nine Old Men and Prehistoric Sluggers Play by play Colonel Stoopnagle interviewed arguing with umpire August 15th, 1937 5:00 - 5:30 pm NBC Blue Part 2 and 4 of 8 [Part 4 unlabeled but assumed]
    - Novelty Baseball Game, 1937 (Folder 77.05, Box 1835)
      Nine Old Men and Prehistoric Sluggers Play by play Colonel Stoopnagle interviewed arguing with umpire August 15th, 1937 5:00 - 5:30 pm NBC Blue Part 5 and 7 of 8 [Part 7 unlabeled but assumed]
    - Novelty Baseball Game, 1937 (Folder 77.06, Box 1835)
      Nine Old Men and Prehistoric Sluggers Play by play Colonel Stoopnagle interviewed arguing with umpire August 15th, 1937 5:00 - 5:30 pm NBC Blue Part 5 and 7 of 8 [Part 5 unlabeled but assumed]
    - Novelty Baseball Game, 1937 (Folder 77.07, Box 1835)
      Nine Old Men and Prehistoric Sluggers Play by play August 15th, 1937 5:00 - 5:30 pm NBC Blue Part 6 and 8 of 8
    - Novelty Baseball Game, 1937 (Folder 77.08, Box 1835)
    - Armed Forces Day, 1950 (Folder 77.09, Box 1835)
      with Lowell Thomas Speeches and Marine Band speaking about NATO May 20th 2:30 - 3:00 pm - 5/1/50 Side 1 and Side 3 [with booklet]
    - Armed Forces Day, 1950 (Folder 77.10, Box 1835)
      with Lowell Thomas Speeches, Cold War era Military Bands 2:30 - 3:00 pm - 5/1/50 Side 2 [with booklet]
    - News Broadcast - Political Analysis Pre-War, 1941 (Folder 77.11, Box 1835)
      Lowell Thomas Blue Sunoco; about the Presidential Broadcast must maintain army, Monroe Doctrine, widening the Draft, Senator Elbert D. Thomas of Utah Declaration of National Emergency Fighting in Smolensk, Eastern Front American 5th Columnists Webber and Fields, Tall Tale NBC Blue 7/21/41, 6:45 Sides 1 and 3
    - Dinner in Honor, 1952 (Folder 77.12, Box 1835)
      Dinner in Honor of His Majesty King Faisal II & His Royal Highness Prince Abdul Ilah Thomas J. Watson; Iraq, Ur, Industry Selection by Baroness Daubeck from Prague 8/13/52 Part 1 and 2
    - Dinner in Honor, 1952 (Folder 77.13, Box 1835)
      Dinner in Honor of His Majesty King Faisal II & His Royal Highness Prince Abdul Ilah Selections by Baroness Daubeck from Prague 8/13/52 Part 3 and 4
    - Dinner in Honor, 1952 (Folder 77.14, Box 1835)
      Dinner in Honor of His Majesty King Faisal II & His Royal Highness Prince Abdul Ilah Thomas J. Watson; Lowell Thomas Eden, Mesopotamia Jokes 8/13/52 Part 5 and 6
    - Dinner in Honor, 1952 (Folder 77.15, Box 1835)
      Dinner in Honor of His Majesty King Faisal II & His Royal Highness Prince Abdul Ilah Lowell Thomas Descendants of Mohammed 8/13/52 Part 7 and 8
    - Dinner in Honor, 1952 (Folder 77.16, Box 1835)
      Dinner in Honor of His Majesty King Faisal II & His Royal Highness Prince Abdul Ilah Lowell Thomas; Thomas J. Watson Honorable Edward S. Crocker II 8/13/52 Part 9 and 10
    - Dinner in Honor, 1952 (Folder 77.17, Box 1835)
      Dinner in Honor of His Majesty King Faisal II & His Royal Highness Prince Abdul Ilah Honorable Warren R. Austin; Thomas J. Watson; Honorable Edward S. Crocker 8/13/52 Part 11 and 12
    - Dinner in Honor, 1952 (Folder 77.18, Box 1835)
      Dinner in Honor of His Majesty King Faisal II & His Royal Highness Prince Abdul Ilah Lowell Thomas; Thomas J. Watson; King Faisal II 8/13/52 Part 13 and 14
    - Recorded Speech for Plaza Banquet, circa 1939 (Folder 77.19, Box 1835)
      Visitors from Pikes Peak, Colorado Hitler’s impending Invasion of Britain American Colony in Jerusalem Benefit at Waldorf with Doctor and Mrs. Lloyd Shaw Revival of Square Dancing Introduction of Herbert Hoover Representative from Stain: Colonel Lewoski Stupnagleovitch [Colonel Stoopnagle] Side A and B
    - Recorded Speech for Plaza Banquet, circa 1939 (Folder 77.20, Box 1835)
      Thomas Dewey Presidential Run Summer White House Upstate Move Capital to Pawling New Deal; Governor of Colorado Ralph Lawrence Carr Tom Beck; Percy Waxman George Bye; Floyd Oddlam More Coronel Stoopnagle Side C and D
    - Recorded Speech for Plaza Banquet, circa 1939 (Folder 77.21, Box 1835)
      Attendees Doctor Roy Chapman Andrews, Gilbert T. Andrews, Frank Mason, Lee Eastman, Truman Talley, John Gunther, Doctor Yu, Doctor Roy Carson, Leray van Bomel McClellan [McClelland?] Barkley, Butron Barkley Phil Cook, W. T. Grant Osa Johnson, Tommy Hitchcock, Jr. [Sr.?] Thomas Lamont, Samuel Pryor, John Mulholland, Dan Parker, Colornel Richard Patterson, Stuart Roby, Milton Cross, Hugh James, Jacques Charmoz, Joe Ryan, Roland Palmedo, Bob Davis, the 9 Old Men On and On and On… Side E, Disk #4
    - “Young Mr. Lincoln”, 1939 (Folder 77.22, Box 1835)
      S1: Lowell Thomas speaking in Springfield Illinois at the Fox Lincoln Theater at the Premier of “Young Mr. Lincoln” celebrating the great emancipator introduces Marian Anderson S2: Young Lincoln looks like Henry Fonda 20th Century Fox Picture Alice Brady as Abigail Clay speaks 5/30/39 WOR Parts 1 and 3
    - “Young Mr. Lincoln”, 1939 (Folder 77.23, Box 1835)
      S1: Premier continued Marian Anderson signing “My Country ‘Tis of Thee” S2: Arlene Whalen as Sarah Clay speaks Eddie Collins as Efe Turner speaks Binnie Barnes speaks 5/30/39 WOR Parts 2 and 4
    - “Young Mr. Lincoln”, 1939 (Folder 77.24, Box 1835)
      Premier continued S1:Caesar Romero speaks Empty Lecture Hall Story Reintroduces Marian Anderson S2: Singing concluded Lowell Thomas concludes 5/30/39 WOR Parts 5 and 7
    - “Young Mr. Lincoln”, 1939 (Folder 77.25, Box 1835)
      Premier continued Marian Anderson singing 5/30/39 WOR Part 6
    - U.S. Armed Forced Institute, undated (Folder 77.26, Box 1835)
      Spanish Side 1 and 2
    - U.S. Armed Forced Institute, undated (Folder 77.27, Box 1835)
      Spanish To be used with Russian Language Guide Side 3 and 4
    - U.S. Armed Forced Institute, undated (Folder 77.28, Box 1835)
      Russian (Revised) To be used with Russian Language Guide Side 1 and 2 [with booklet]
    - U.S. Armed Forced Institute, undated (Folder 77.29, Box 1835)
      Russian (Revised) To be used with Russian Language Guide Side 3 and 4 [with booklet]
    - U.S. Armed Forced Institute, undated (Folder 77.30, Box 1835)
      Italian To be used with Italian Language Guide Side 1 and 2 [with booklet]
    - U.S. Armed Forced Institute, undated (Folder 77.31, Box 1835)
      Italian To be used with Italian Language Guide Side 3 and 4 [with booklet]
    - Opening Five Minutes of Lowell Thomas Newscast, 1936 (Folder 77.32, Box 1836)
      Thomas Robinson Jr. confessed Kidnapping of Alice Speed Stoll in Louisville, Kentucky J Edgar Hoover announced Dressed as woman Death Penalty in Kentucky will plead insanity, was institutionalized Pat Withrow speaks on crime call for inflation in Congress Blue Sunoco WJZ - 5/12/36
    - Advertising Club Luncheon, 1937 (Folder 77.33, Box 1836)
      Tribute to National Business Show S1: Bruce Barton, guest speaker and President Thomas J. Watson from the Hague Frederick W. Nichol Lowell Thomas Speaking S2: Vice President of IBM, F. W. Nichol speaks 10/21/37 Parts 1 and 3
    - Advertising Club Luncheon, 1937 (Folder 77.34, Box 1836)
      Tribute to National Business Show S1: Largest Gavel in the World list of future guests Judge Mahoney, Mayor LaGuardia The Office Equipment Industry S2: F. W. Nichol Concludes 10/21/37 Parts 2 and 4
    - Advertising Club Luncheon, 1937 (Folder 77.35, Box 1836)
      Tribute to National Business Show Lowell Thomas Speaking Executive Vice President Don Stoll [sp?] speaking Exportation of American Industry 10/21/37 Parts 5 and 7
    - Advertising Club Luncheon, 1937 (Folder 77.36, Box 1836)
      Tribute to National Business Show S1: President of Dictaphone Corporation, Mr. Earl Sands speaks, introduced by Lowell Thomas S2: Thomas J. Watson Speaking Economic Harmony ends threat of another European War 10/21/37 Parts 6 and 8
    - Advertising Club Luncheon, 1937 (Folder 77.37, Box 1836)
      Tribute to National Business Show 10/21/37 Parts 9 and 11
    - Advertising Club Luncheon, 1937 (Folder 77.38, Box 1836)
      Tribute to National Business Show 10/21/37 Parts 10 and 12
    - Advertising Club Luncheon, 1937 (Folder 77.39, Box 1836)
      Tribute to National Business Show 10/21/37 Parts 13 and 14
    - Sepp Molinger, undated (Folder 77.40, Box 1836)
      [Austrian Ski Instructor?] Yodeling Part 1 and 2
    - Sepp Molinger, undated (Folder 77.41, Box 1836)
      [same as 59.38] Part 1 and 2
    - Lowell Thomas Commercials, circa 1954 (Folder 77.42, Box 1836)
      For Broadcast: Wed 2/17/54
    - Lowell Thomas Commercials, circa 1954 (Folder 77.43, Box 1836)
      For Broadcast: Tue 2/16/54
    - Lowell Thomas Commercials, circa 1954 (Folder 77.44, Box 1836)
    - Lowell Thomas Commercials, circa 1954 (Folder 77.45, Box 1836)
      For Broadcast: Thur 2/18/54
    - Lowell Thomas Commercials, circa 1954 (Folder 77.46, Box 1836)
      For Broadcast: Fri 2/19/54
    - Lowell Thomas Commercials, circa 1954 (Folder 77.47, Box 1836)
    - Lowell Thomas Commercials, undated (Folder 77.48, Box 1836)
      Unlabeled; Collection of Ivory Soap Commercials “Your Hands aren’t made of China” “It Floats!”
    - Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 77.49, Box 1836)
      September 29, 1930 Part 3 of 3
    - Lowell Thomas Commercials, circa 1954 (Folder 77.50, Box 1836)
    - Lowell Thomas Commercials, circa 1954 (Folder 77.51, Box 1836)
      For Broadcast: Mon 2/15/54
    - Lowell Thomas Commercials, circa 1954 (Folder 77.52, Box 1836)
    - Sound Effects (Folder 77.53, Box 1836)
      Inside out: Atomic Bomb Outside out: Crowd Cheering
    - Sound Effects, 1946 (Folder 77.54, Box 1836)
      Atomic Bomb - Rumble Recorded for: Mr. Lowell Thomas October 10th, 1946
    - John Winters, 1936 (Folder 77.55, Box 1836)
      With Lowell Thomas July 29th, 1936 9:15 - 9:30 pm Parts 1 and 3 of 3 Organ Background Flight from Canada to Baghdad Trans-World Record New Guinea
    - John Winters, 1936 (Folder 77.56, Box 1836)
      With Lowell Thomas July 29th, 1936 9:15 - 9:30 pm Part 2 Organ Background “Powdering the Lion’s Face” Dolores, Beauty of London “Hilarious” Herbert Hoover’s 60th Birthday
    - Lowell Thomas, 1930 (Folder 77.57, Box 1836)
      September 29th, 1930 Parts 1 and [assumed] 2 German Political Mix-up Fascists in Germany and Spain Denouncement of King Alfonzo Threats of War in Andorra Hamburg, Inflation, dumping products Socialist meeting in Paris, attack on Police
    - Lowell Thomas, 1939 (Folder 77.58, Box 1836)
      World Series Game 2 Pre-Game 10/5/39 Sides 1 and 2 LT as Sports Commentator Al Schacht Herbert Hoover in Stands Ford Frick Judge Kennesaw Mountain Landis Lou Gehrig, Lefty Gomez, Powel Crosley, National Anthem Joe DiMaggio, Bill Dickey, Babe Ruth, Red Barber
    - Lowell Thomas, 1936 (Folder 77.59, Box 1836)
      WJZ, May 25th, 1936 (with Musical interpolations - test record) Parts 3 and 4 Organ Music Judicial Threat on New Deal Supreme Court Ruling Republican Convention Governor Frank Louden Social Security Act Organ Music Nominated Norman Thomas for Socialists
    - Opening of Museum of Arts, 1939 (Folder 77.60, Box 1836)
      Lowell Thomas and Nelson Rockefeller III NBC Blue, 10:00 - 11: 00 pm May 10th, 1939 Rockefeller as President of Museum of Modern Art Nine Old Men World’s Fair Art of the Past 50 Years Alfred Barr
    - Rimpoche Speaks, undated (Folder 77.61, Box 1836)
      Record #10 Not in English
    - Unlabeled 1941 Broadcast (Folder 77.62, Box 1836)
      Unlabeled S1: Inflation since March 1933 Beneficial now, will become harmful Reduction in Car Production Chlorine rationed, now newspapers yellow Expulsion of Nazi Minister from Bolivia Rumors of Invasion of Portugal Invasion of Crete Bombing of Berlin Guerrilla War in Moscow 5th Air raid on Moscow S2: Music
    - Blank Label, undated (Folder 78.01, Box 1837)
      Handwritten 2 on one side, 4 on other
    - “Your Portrait in Sound”, undated (Folder 78.02, Box 1837)
      Crawford Livingston
    - No Label, undated (Folder 78.03, Box 1837)
      On sleeve: Nelson Case - Ivory Commercial
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1954 (Folder 78.04, Box 1837)
      Harry Marble Commercials For Monday February 8th, 1954 All Cuts Identical Willys Motor Inc. Ewell Thurber Associates Side 1: Openings Side 2: Closings
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1954 (Folder 78.05, Box 1837)
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1954 (Folder 78.06, Box 1837)
      Harry Marble Commercials For Tuesday February 9th, 1954 All Cuts Identical Willys Motor Inc. Ewell Thurber Associates Side 1: Openings Side 2: Closings
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1954 (Folder 78.07, Box 1837)
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1954 (Folder 78.08, Box 1837)
      Harry Marble Commercials For Wednesday February 10th, 1954 All Cuts Identical Willys Motor Inc. Ewell Thurber Associates Side 1: Openings Side 2: Closings
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1954 (Folder 78.09, Box 1837)
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1954 (Folder 78.10, Box 1837)
      Harry Marble Commercials For Thursday February 11th, 1954 All Cuts Identical Willys Motor Inc. Ewell Thurber Associates Side 1: Openings Side 2: Closings
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1954 (Folder 78.11, Box 1837)
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1954 (Folder 78.12, Box 1837)
      Harry Marble Commercials For Friday February 12th, 1954 All Cuts Identical Willys Motor Inc. Ewell Thurber Associates Side 1: Openings Side 2: Closings
    - Lowell Thomas Program, 1954 (Folder 78.13, Box 1837)
    - Hi Jinx, 1948 (Folder 78.14, Box 1837)
      March 30th, 1948 Parts 1 and 4
    - Hi Jinx, 1948 (Folder 78.15, Box 1837)
      March 30th, 1948 Parts 2 and 5
    - Hi Jinx, 1948 (Folder 78.16, Box 1837)
      March 30th, 1948 Parts 3 and 6
    - The Family Altar, undated (Folder 78.17, Box 1837)
      Family Altar Records Inc. “The Family Altar - Alters the Family” Dr. Norman Vincent Peale & Mr. Lowell Thomas Organist: Mr. Harry Fussner Band 1: Monday Band 2: Tuesday Band 3: Wednesday Side 1 and 2
    - Mary Howard Recordings, 1950 (Folder 78.18, Box 1837)
      Lowell Thomas April 4th, 1950 Reading of Howard Morgan into. Made at K[call sign?], LA, California
    - Lowell Thomas Break-up, 1955 (Folder 78.19, Box 1837)
      December 12th, 1955
    - Lowell Thomas, 1939 (Folder 78.20, Box 1837)
      Interviewed by Liza Sergio WQXR May 5th, 1939 Parts 1 and 3
    - Lowell Thomas, 1939 (Folder 78.21, Box 1837)
      Interviewed by Liza Sergio WQXR May 5th, 1939 Parts 2 and 4
    - Lowell Thomas, 1936 (Folder 78.22, Box 1837)
      Lowell Thomas newscast May 25th, 1936 - WJZ (with musical interpolations - test record) Side 1 and 2
    - Women Can Take It, 1943 (Folder 78.23, Box 1837)
      Mrs. Lowell Thomas and Others WYMCA, March 24th, 1943 Side 1 and 2
    - Women Can Take It, 1943 (Folder 78.24, Box 1837)
      Mrs. Lowell Thomas and Others WYMCA, March 24th, 1943 Side 3